This marriage ain't big enough for the both of them.
The Roses is a comedy, drama film directed by Jay Roach.
Life seems easy for picture-perfect couple Ivy and Theo:
successful careers, a loving marriage, great kids.
But beneath the façade of their supposed ideal life, a storm is brewing – as Theo's career nosedives while
Ivy's own ambitions take off, a tinderbox of fierce competition and hidden resentment ignites.
Ivy Rose, played by Olivia Colman.
Theo Rose, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
Barry, played by Andy Samberg.
Amy, played by Kate McKinnon.
Janice, played by Belinda Bromilow.
Jeffrey, played by Ncuti Gatwa.
The Roses is a 2025 satirical black comedy film directed by
Jay Roach from a screenplay by Tony McNamara.
It is based on the 1981 novel The War of the Roses by Warren Adler, and
a reimagining of the 1989 film The War of the Roses.
The film stars Benedict Cumberbatch and Olivia Colman as a successful couple
whose seemingly picture-perfect marriage begins falling apart.
Andy Samberg, Allison Janney, Belinda Bromilow, Sunita Mani, Ncuti Gatwa, Jamie
Demetriou, Zoë Chao, and Kate McKinnon appear in supporting roles.
The Roses was released in the United States by
Searchlight Pictures on August 29, 2025.
It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $52 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, based on
novel or book, dark comedy, remake, failing marriage.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.